Guide to the Calhoun College, Yale University, Student Records for the Classes of 1934-1974 Maintained by the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Calhoun College, Yale University, student records for the Classes of 1934-1974 maintained by the master
RU 795
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.08
(11 boxes)
The records consist of student records maintained by the master of Calhoun College, Yale University. Only withdrawals are represented for the Classes of 1968-1974. Some administrative files are also included.
Calhoun College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-E-2 (YRG 13-E-2), Records of the master of Calhoun College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of student records maintained by the master of Calhoun College, Yale University. Only withdrawals are represented for the Classes of 1968-1974. Some administrative files are also included.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
College students; Calhoun College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students
- Student records and administrative files, circa 1934-1973; Accession 1972-A-012
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2049
  Scope and Contents
  Paper inventory with full listing of contents for boxes 1-7 available in repository.
  - Student transcripts
    - Class of 1934
    - Class of 1935
    - Class of 1936
    - Class of 1937
    - Class of 1938
    - Class of 1939
    - Class of 1940
    - Class of 1941
    - Class of 1942
    - Class of 1943
    - Class of 1944
      General
      Degrees were awarded in October of 1943 (classes ran year-round during war).
    - Class of 1945
    - Class of 1946
    - Class of 1947
    - Class of 1948
    - Class of 1949
    - Class of 1950
    - Class of 1951
    - Class of 1952
    - Class of 1953
    - Class of 1954
    - Class of 1955
  - Dean Carroll's files, 1956-1963 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    Material primarily consists of police reorts and correspondence relating to disciplinary matters. There is also a small amount of general administrative correspondence.
  - War Casualties, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Deceased students (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Withdrawals
  - Student records
    - Class of 1956
    - Class of 1957
    - Class of 1958
    - Class of 1959
    - Class of 1960
    - Class of 1961
    - Class of 1962
    - Class of 1963
    - Class of 1964
    - Class of 1965
    - Class of 1966
    - Class of 1967